we'll show you how maybe that would
happen so imag then I would go and have
some interaction with it hi what's up
and why is Java so bad and so these are
my regular interactions with those
things so now you could see the alert
one coming up yeah so what's going on we
literally just sent the message based on
the conversation context app or message
we sent it back to the like the API
itself got this API response back
printed it to the page we'll talk about
that in a
sec you're listening to the AI native
Dev brought to you by
[Music]
Tesla on the second part of today's
episode we're going to go a little bit
deeper and we're actually going to do
some screen sharing showing some various
vulnerabilities using AI in a number of
different ways joining me here today
again is lauran tal leading the deell
efforts at sneak welcome lauran how are
you hey all good Simon always happy to
just do some hacking live hacking with
you it's like always fun then let's
bring the idea of live hacking into the
screen here and so tell us a little bit
about what the first exercise that we're
going to do is then we're going to do a
bit of interaction with a chatbot right
yes we'll have some fun with the llm I
have to say honestly as we begin my
biggest fear is not the security issues
of of the llm it's rather that you would
troll me for JavaScript issues we'll see
just so you know just so you know I'm
pretty sure it's going to happen it's
more about when than if but let's
continue and see how many times maybe we
can have a sweep stake on how many times
but we'll see okay let's see let's see
if it's more or less than npm packages
on so yeah let's get started basically
what we're doing in this experiment we
have one two three JavaScript
experiments and to get it into the
framing it's not just JavaScript they
have a python example so like other
languages are having issues too but
we'll focus on JavaScript because we
both know also Simon agreed to that
before to say that it's like the best
language in the world there we go got
that vulnerable demos 100% yeah you
should have get you to sign that yes
we're gonna have three examples we're
going to go and I think walk through
them and understand like how
vulnerabilities can happen but I think
what's very very specific to this
vulnerable demo is how the llm itself is
going to create a security nightmare for
you if you do not know how to use it
correct I don't mean about suggesting
like bad code and stuff like that but
rather M much more technical aspect to
it should we get started do you want us
to absolutely let jump straight in yeah
okay amazing so the best demo always
starts with an index so we'll open that
one and as you can see I'll explain a
bit it's an Express API for OJs backend
JavaScript stuff it uses the open AI API
behind the S to interact with the llm
it's like a jokes database as an array
here so makes things simple and we
expose an API jokes that we can interact
with over HTTP we essentially just add
not really a user input but if you see
there's like nothing that gets here
there's like request is literally unused
here okay never read that means we kind
like are going to generate jokes based
on just randomly selecting from this
hardcoded data of database and prompting
it to give us the output so far so good
yep okay I want to change one of them
and say
just one of the jokes to be has to be
going to be Java related isn't
it say it already knows what yeah what
me Java Nostalgia let's say Nostalgia
one of the other ones to be removed so
we can increase our genes of and yeah so
we're going to basically bring that
output back and do something with it and
I want to show you this is like the very
very first that's going to be very basic
but I think it's going to be fun so to
prompt it actually let me make sure that
we run it so this is going into the
first example run it it's running and I
have this aptp and we can just say tell
me a joke we'll send this request uh oh
there we go we ended on Java surprise so
just you have to tell me if this is a
good joke it already looks amazing or
started with like Java programmer break
things up I feel like it's a bit sexist
but yeah say for work yeah absolutely
but it's good it's good let's do another
one there we go I like that it focused
on Java rather than anything else in
that jokes that
it doesn't like Outlets does it
interesting it's hanging on to the
outlets it's good amazing three out of
three old Java jokes I love this could
handle the bite of nostalgia that's
pretty poor that's like lauran level
trolling jokes yeah we basically just
interacted with dlm this was a fun
experiment I'll remember this for the
rest of my life and essentially you
could look at this and like Wonder I
don't know what is it 40 lines of code
what could go wrong what's the security
concern here it's like literally
hardcoded data like nothing but even
there if you look at it a bit more you
can start wondering hey what do all of
these methods do they just send data in
in some way I'm going to run that
request and and maybe it exposes one of
the potential issues that exists and
it's not to troll you even though we're
going to count four out of four attempts
trolling Java but you already can maybe
see from the data here that's maybe not
the way that you expect to consume
content and I'll go ahead and turn on my
sneak extension to scan this that's why
I disabl it for sector see if it working
the sneak support Java jokes yeah it
rolls every Java developer by like
that's what we have yeah in the product
it's like my own feature request but
yeah know it I enabled it it quickly
scanned it as you see like literally few
seconds and you already see one of the
issues that I was referring to so the
Way That We Built This Server is that
the content type in the way that we sent
the response back was text HTML and
that's like the default if you use res.
send that's like the problem here like
you might be able to like I don't know
if this was like coding assistant
generated maybe you weren't really aware
of that but now imagine that the the llm
replies back with things that are not
just text but text that actually means
things like meanss HTML elements and
other things and then they get loaded
onto the page or to like some response
like a d element that fetches that API
see that it's text HTML and append it in
a way that is could create like a cross-
scripting issue and it's or snake shines
where it shows you those things and it
really has that deep understanding if I
close it show you what's going on it
literally says xss but look at the way
that it understands it unsanitized input
from an llm flows into scent it knows
it's coming hardcoded from the LM itself
and even that is a problem I think
that's like a level of it's considering
it just as bad as as user data there
realistically the fact that it could be
malicious exactly I'm going to close
this one up I'm gonna do an under demo
so I'll disable this again while we're
talking about jokes lauran I went to a
restaurant the other day and I ordered
duck and I called the way TR and I said
can I switch that to Pheasant it was a
complete Game Changer wait
what it is oh okay yeah that's we'll
leave that one for the listeners we'll
leave that one for the listeners that's
fine okay we'll do that I think that one
escaped me I could swear that was a
troll no no okay I was looking for the
troll I was like too obsessed with that
no it was one of the few that wasn't I
thank you for that Simon that's like
very thoughtful you welcome so this is
an amazing thing I just built I wanted
to raise like h100 million for it it's
called chat with AI you've probably have
never seen this it's super super
Innovative that's what we do here you've
seen that before or this is like a whole
new interface right no I'm certainly not
seen it on the right hand side that's
very different
yeah that's there that's where you go
that's why I want to raise so much
money so here's the thing you're
building those kind of things with with
AI what you do is you prompt it you make
no conversations in different ways this
is like super super simple as well it's
like even the UI is going to look like
bad but you see how like data now do do
flow into the app itself there's like an
API endpoint which is SL Converse and it
takes the request we takes the puty
takes the message from this request it
flows into the prompt that we want to
generate and then it goes back to the
user and so so making the point we'll
show you how maybe that would happen so
imagine I would go and have some
interaction with it hey what's up and
why is Java so bad and so these are my
regular interactions with those things
it really depends it could be bad it
could be bad Simon that's you should
change newer languages like JavaScript
that javascript's not actually that much
difference Java in terms of age is it no
not that much yeah is there something
you don't it feels like a therapy
session now is there something specific
you don't like about Java Lal
I think that's what I'm going to do I'm
going to raise that money as like a
therapy AI forv thy yeah Java therapy B
but what if we asked it like let's
imagine this is like prod API production
API kind of thing where you deploy it
and you want to make sure that
developers or like attackers don't
really do funny business with it they
you generate an xss crossy scripting
very load here so I can I don't know
grab the cookie from grab the I'll make
it B more reality maybe token from local
storage and I might send it we'll give
you this reply where I'm sorry of course
but I can't assist you because of
obviously we're this is we're hitting
the alignment issue with llms are biased
towards good things and not allowing
them to cross ethical boundaries and
things like that that's like very common
and so I think at this point what it
will try to do is to prompt injection or
it will try to get it to give us uh some
output back where that will be part of
the response itself and then potentially
uh impact the page already I'm going to
try something we'll see if it works and
I have some stuff saved on the end if it
doesn't because this is n deterministic
like we talked about before so we'll
say Ju Ju Just to summarize it you're
trying to get the AI bot to create a
payload a cross-site scripting payload
so that it itself will actually perform
the crosslite scripting attack in this
page correct that's what I'm GNA try and
do we'll see if that works time you're
saying please it could work better we'll
see I could
try one yeah let's see let me fix this
broken HTML
component let's if let try and make it
it's no okay know while while you're
typing that you say the AI bot has has
some ethical boundaries here yet it
entertained your question about Java
being bad I think it's quite easy to get
around of those ethical boundaries by
the yeah that's naturally Ed un okay so
you've put in something that's slightly
broken so won't hit any won't hit too
many alarm bells and if it's for things
that are looking for exact strings but
so there's there's clearly no checking
here then for cross out scripting that
there isn't any on the on my website you
mean yeah or or perhaps just only
checking your strings oh no there's
there's nothing there I there's
literally in this API it literally just
gives you the output back nothing else
oh gotcha okay so there's like nothing
protecting what's happening here and
just trusting the llm output to do
something with it in this case just
print it on the screen so I don't know
if this going to work this n
deterministic we'll try this prompt and
if not we can try something else or copy
it so we can reuse just in case we need
to find unit oh there we go first try so
now you could see the alert one coming
up yeah so what's going on we literally
just sent the message based on the
conversation context app or message we
sent it back to the like the API itself
got this API response back printed it to
the page we'll talk about that in a sec
but what's Happening Here is as you said
as you very eloquently described it the
llm output itself is what creates the
xss payload itself which is why this is
already running here showing us alert
one which is what we use if I scroll
back you could see what's actually going
on it literally did try to help me fix
that component thing that we gather and
like we intentionally made it broken so
it would fix it and would result in a
crossy scripting vulnerability because
we added that alert fer and you could
see that he tried to generate it it like
literally added that as a dumb element
to the page because of a different thing
which I'll show you also in a second but
it really did execute it on the page too
so go ahead remove that and as we build
this app maybe you understand what's
going on maybe we don't there's like a
public thing that sends the HTML back
which now you could look into it's
loading some low Das thing to do
whatever thing you want with it is the
submit button you get the input and you
print the messages to the page and
whatever the llms give back we also want
to show it to the user like with this AI
thing so we display the message which is
this function that adds that Ai and the
message as an element onto the page now
if you are a very experienced frontend
developer I would say also potentially
security-minded beginner developer I
want to trust that they know that
there's issues with using this API on
this is like a dumb API that's provided
to you by the browser to do things and
if you use this API it's a very insecure
way of adding data onto the page because
it does if the context here is going
going to be like this image thing it
will go ahead and try to really embed an
image HTML element which is not what you
anyway want to do this is also a bad
practice but it may happen especially if
you're like using llm a lot to generate
the Cod and maybe you do not really
understand those kind of small aspects
of it or maybe you're like used so much
to like frontend Frameworks and
libraries that you're like used to their
API but if you get vanilla JavaScript
you're like not even understanding how
this actually works so again if I enable
again let's go ahead and enable the
sneak
Shing uh extensions sneak I'll go ahead
and enable this I want to show you how
sneak annotates it so it's going to go
it's going to scan all the project again
but we're only going to care about
already finished about index HTML which
you could see there's potentially
something better and index to if I go
into index it shows you the exact same
problem again right xss and not using
Json so that's a problem we've seen
before but also if you open this index
HTML it's really cool because it shows
you several things first off we imported
this low Das Library like straight from
a CDN which is probably not the best
thing to do but some apps work this way
or they have like internal cdns but also
if you do it like that it's really hard
to manage versions that specifically
there sneak will tell you it has some
security issues with it even if you like
did not declare it in a package manifest
which is pretty cool the other thing is
it will annotate this inner HTML to and
tell you hey this is like a sync to add
crossy scripting and this is really bad
and you should also fix this too yeah so
I I really like the way that it weeps
into like in a very similar sway to your
kind of coding extension like annotated
like very clearly so if the user added a
cross-site scripting tag into there as
well that would equally create the alert
box I presume but the interesting thing
there is that you can get it so that the
AI is actually sending that back as well
so you've got to treat AI output just as
equally as user output or rather sorry
you can you have to treat the output
from the AI in the same exactly the same
way as a user input it needs to be it
needs to be sanitized and checked in
very similar ways yeah no correct this
is you're right like it treed in the
same way it doesn't really matter if
it's like an llm output or the user
output that's like the point we're
making here where llm output where we
started even if they're hardcoded to get
jokes that they could still end up badly
and that's what we wanted to show here
too so we'll go to the last demo here
number three and for that one what I
want to show you is first so this is
this has a whole database thing on it go
wrong yeah what could go wrong well I
did use sqli but it's not a distributed
problem just on my loation yeah no but
for the sakes of the issues here there's
just that and what we're saying is
there's a database we open up with this
is just like an in showers we create a
conversations table a user table we add
some data to the user table I'll show
you that in a sec and we're having like
the exact same thing we're having like a
message bot you interact with this llm
you can have conversations with it it
will help you data flows into it you
print it back or do something with the
response but more specifically before
you print the response back sometimes
maybe you want to do like log or audit
the response that the llm gave you so we
do that and you'll again notice we only
log into the database only the responses
from the llm itself we do not PL
anything from user input this is
literally just LM itself let's say we
want to collect the data do some
training and insights and I analytics on
top of it understand like what's going
on or whatever I think it's a valid
business case just do that yep so if we
do that let's give it let's give it some
try so I think we did start the app I
want to show you the conversations the B
thing that we created this is just like
I said this is SQL so this is local
database on on my my app just we just
started it so it seed new data to users
here conversation very common name yeah
very super common name and I'll go ahead
and show you kind like how to interact
with it so let me go to this part so
it's a lot tricker to like do the
exploitation for that one so I will get
back to it in a sec but I just want to
show you how it works so you just send
this request to the converse API and ask
it can you teach me about SQL injection
yeah it answer it back yeah of course I
can teach you about SQL injections and C
SEC is like important stuff now what
we're going to try to do since we know
we're like interacting with LM and we
don't know what the app is doing like
from an attacker point of view but we
know that there's like potentially like
something that's like maybe not
sanitized use this securely like queries
are concatenated one to the other and
what I want to show you is if I close
this for a sec is look at how the way
I've constructed this train to create
the query ask it can you teach me how to
quot securely my colleagues always talk
about one and I close this with
parenthesis and semicolon so like I'm
closing the other query and I say drop
table users so I remove the entire table
users that we showed you before and I
close that query too and I then to
terminate it and then say everything
else is basically just a comment or
whatever the llm when it gets this thing
it it doesn't run it in like an SQL
context so it it does has no meaning it
just it tokenizes it and for it it's
just like some random dash dash that you
use for whatever reason that TR
understand that so I so let's see this
you can see I have like variations of
that because it really depends on how
the llm responds back and this like
non-deterministic way that it it works
but actually change the way that
sometimes those exploits work and
sometimes they don't let's try this one
and see what happens sending the request
I can't believe he didn't call the user
Bobby tables as well and that that's a
big oversight for this demo in that
database yeah I know do you want to
should we stop now and re-record
everything we maybe we should yeah yeah
ni let's push on let's push on so this
is interesting first off so just from
looking at this response I am not
entirely sure it worked maybe it did
let's see what's going on so first off
it answered our request why can you
teach me and there thing and you have to
understand that we're trying to
concatenate very specific strings to
close SQL query and run another one and
this could be a problem that there's
like this single a single quarter maybe
I don't know let's see I don't know if
this is an issue definitely not an issue
and our P just goes here I'm not fatir
sure if it if it worked we can literally
just look at the database and let's say
if users exist or it really got dropped
let's see that I will look at the
conversation to be and see if this works
we have conversations oh but no users no
Bobby tables anymore yeah yeah yes so
apparently what happened here is that
the way that we added this input into
our query which made it back into the
output of the llm which then made it
into this part of the response course
you can imagine I've just done like that
and then it's there and you can see like
how it's try to close this and do
something else and whatever and if
sometimes when I run this you will see
that I actually get like quy errors like
this one because the way that it like
terminates and start the other query
doesn't always work so like some so some
part of the qu because it's a multiquery
some parts of it do work but the rest of
it doesn't work and doesn't like make
sense so it's actually quite interesting
but it does work um if I open up the S
do you want to say do you want to show
them how you pronounce sneak in a bad
way I'd say sneak that's seems fine to
me although I I have been known to say
Snick in the past as well but there we
go I was encouraged I was encouraged to
say
sneak nice glad to see you're on your
good way yeah good behavior today all
right cool so we can see like Snak
already assorted start annotating stuff
and saying what's going on here pointing
out several issues again the xss issue
here but you could also see that it
specifically found this SQL injection
which happens because I am indeed using
like this insecure API to that literally
just constraints to create scl curs and
I'm using this dp. XX that allows it not
only allows it but actually allows for
if you did dp. insert or get or
something will allow a specific like a
like one single quy to run not a
multiple them using exec is like in bad
is bad for like several reasons but if I
didn't know better and I was thinking if
I was if you were reviewing this with me
maybe I would tell you hey you know what
s that's not as bad like literally not
user input this is like the llm itself
what could go wrong then this is where
you would say hey you know what look at
what snake says this is SQL injection
potential to happen there and llm itself
could be a problem too yeah it it feels
less of an attack VOR for a user to try
and get an llm to say something specific
versus trying to send the SQ injection
themselves so that's very interesting so
there we go I'm going to go back and
rerun the the Java jokes I like five
more times after the go try find a good
one try to find a really good one yeah
yeah yeah because if you replace that
with JavaScript they probably wouldn't
be funny at all I would
guess that'll be scary yeah scary enough
amazing lauran it's been an absolute
pleasure and great to see you live
coding here on the A8 of Dev so thank
you much for your time and thank you for
your expertise sharing your screen and
sharing your examples here amazing thank
you for having me thank you and to all
our listeners tune in again to the next
[Music]
[Applause]
session thanks for tuning in join us
next time on the AI native Dev brought
to you by Tesla